<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/stylesheets/rss.css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>deferred until inspiration hits</title>
    <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>

    <description></description>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Javascript QueryString Printer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve used this &lt;a href=&quot;http://httpd.apache.org/docs/1.3/mod/mod_rewrite.html&quot;&gt;mod rewrite&lt;/a&gt; trick in the past to inspect the contents of various &lt;a href=&quot;http://httpd.apache.org/&quot;&gt;apache&lt;/a&gt; variables you have access to.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
# Add this before any other rewrite rules in your apache config or .htaccess
RewriteRule .* http://foo?request_uri=%{REQUEST_URI}&amp;#38;the_request=%{THE_REQUEST}&amp;#38;host=%{HTTP_HOST}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Although useful, it&amp;#8217;s kinda hard to inspect the variables when they&amp;#8217;re in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  It dawned on me that it would be easier to see them if they were in a page in the browser itself.  So, I knocked up a simple little html page that uses javascript to extract the querystring key/value pairs and display them on the page.  It doesn&amp;#8217;t look very pretty but it makes it much easier to see the content of the variables.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The page is hosted in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisroos.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/querystring-printer/&quot;&gt;google code repository&lt;/a&gt; and there&amp;#8217;s a splendid little screenshot below.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3288/3082048735_f76b44712e.jpg?v=0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;At the moment you&amp;#8217;ll need to host this file yourself, but if there&amp;#8217;s demand then I can probably make it publicly available somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 10:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:31745701-a13d-40e0-9702-13029cf02ca9</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-12-05-a-javascript-querystring-printer</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OCR on the Mac with Tesseract</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_character_recognition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OCR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; another letter this morning and, as &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2008-07-21-open-source-optical-character-recognition-ocr-on-the-mac&quot;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;, I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/tesseract-ocr/&quot;&gt;tesseract&lt;/a&gt; for the job.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I ended up spending some time testing the quality of the output (the generated text) against different quality inputs (as defined by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dots_per_inch&quot;&gt;dpi&lt;/a&gt; setting in my scanner software).  The results were not surprising. The best output, with only a couple of errors in the whole letter, came from the 300dpi scan (the highest I tried). The scan at 150dpi contained a handful of mistakes and at 96dpi the output was, in places, complete gibberish.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;In case this is of use to anyone I have copies of the, smaller, second page of the letter I was scanning, along with the OCRd output.  The scanner is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.epson.co.uk/products/all_in_one_products/Stylus_DX4800.htm&quot;&gt;Epson Stylus &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DX4800&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://seashore.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;seashore&lt;/a&gt; to convert the images, from colour jpegs, to greyscale tiffs.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h2&gt;At 300dpi&lt;/h2&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/chrisjroos/3076819819/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3202/3076819819_d4f1a3f3cd_t.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
Nothing is ruled out in terms of further development, and I have met with a representative of mySociety to discuss ways of continuing to improve what we do.
I am fully supportive of the aims of the Free Our Bills campaign, and I am keen to work with the relevant House authorities to see what can be done to open up the legislative process to a broader audience.
I hope that this is helpful to your constituent.
&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;h2&gt;At 150dpi&lt;/h2&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/chrisjroos/3076622097/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3202/3076819819_d4f1a3f3cd_t.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
Nothing is ruled out in terms of further development, and I have met with a representative of mySociety to discuss ways of continuing to improve what we do.
I am fully supportive ofthe aims ofthe Free Our Bills campaign, and I am keen to work with the relevant House authorities to see what can be done to open up the legislative process to a broader audience.
I hope that this is helpful to your constituent.
&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;h2&gt;At 96dpi&lt;/h2&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/chrisjroos/3076624115/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3202/3076819819_d4f1a3f3cd_t.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
Nothing is ruled out in tcmts cI` further develcpntcnt, and I have met with u rcpresentmivc ul&amp;#8217; mysociety tn discuss ways nfccnvsinuing to improve what we dc.
I am titlly supportive oI&amp;#8217;thc uirns ofthe I-`rce Our Bills campaign, und I urn keen vn work with the relevant House authorities to sec what can he done to open up thc legislative process In at broader audience.
I hope that this is hclphtl to your constituent.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 16:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:f997836c-86e2-409a-80c7-9601dd3dbfe8</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-12-02-ocr-on-the-mac-with-tesseract</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Listening to iTunes on my Intempo GX-01</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve had the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intempodigital.com/GX-01/AJ100008,en_GB,pd.html&quot;&gt;Intempo GX-01&lt;/a&gt; for a while but have only just felt the need to play my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/itunes/&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; library through it.  It turns out that I needed something that could share my iTunes library using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Plug_and_Play&quot;&gt;UPnP&lt;/a&gt; protocol.  I tried a few different applications before finally settling on the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elgato.com/elgato/na/mainmenu/products/software/EyeConnect.en.html&quot;&gt;EyeConnect&lt;/a&gt; application.  Although it&amp;#8217;s commercial software it&amp;#8217;s offered with a free 30 day trial, and, it would appear that even after the 30 days the audio sharing functionality remains free forever.  Yay.  It installs as a preference pane which means you can install it, configure it, set it running and then forget about it: it does what it needs to and gets out of your way.  I&amp;#8217;ve only really dabbled with it at the moment but I&amp;#8217;m certainly impressed with what I&amp;#8217;ve seen so far.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;The alternatives (in the interest of fairness)&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nullriver.com/products/medialink&quot;&gt;Nullriver MediaLink&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; The first application I tried.  I was immediately hooked on the simplicity and would have been more than willing to pay for it.  Unfortunately, although my radio could see my iTunes library, it refused to play any music: The Intempo responded with &amp;#8220;UPnP Internal Error 113&amp;#8221;.  It took me a while to realise that this software was specifically designed for the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PS3&lt;/span&gt; and I can only assume that&amp;#8217;s the reason for the error I received.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allegrosoft.com/ams.html&quot;&gt;Allegro Media Server&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; This worked fine but it felt a bit kludgy.  I&amp;#8217;d guess this was because of the elegance of the Nullriver offering though.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twonkyvision.de/Products/TwonkyMedia/index.html&quot;&gt;TwonkyMedia Media Server&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; As with the Allegro offering this worked fine but felt a little kludgy and over-complicated.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://xbmc.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XBMC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; I&amp;#8217;m afraid I only got as far as downloading, opening the application and immediately closing it.  It was immediately clear that this was far too complicated for what I was after.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 22:50:57 +0100</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:c4456177-2114-4d20-a63e-ac21507de898</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-09-03-listening-to-itunes-on-my-intempo-gx-01</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Changing the repository of code being managed by Piston (an alternative to piston switch)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been working on a little script that gives us visibility of the state of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://piston.rubyforge.org/&quot;&gt;pistonised&lt;/a&gt; components of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reevoo.com&quot;&gt;our&lt;/a&gt; applications.  One of the things I noticed was that we&amp;#8217;d used multiple domains to pistonise content from our own &lt;a href=&quot;http://subversion.tigris.org/&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;.  I wanted to standardise them all and thought I&amp;#8217;d be able to use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blade.nagaokaut.ac.jp/cgi-bin/scat.rb/ruby/ruby-talk/235517&quot;&gt;piston switch&lt;/a&gt; command to do just that.  Unfortunately, the piston switch command appears to work only when switching between URLs where the domain remains constant (switching between example.com/tag/1 and example.com/tag/2, for example).  I needed to change the domain part of the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; (svn.example.com to www.example.com) and in some cases the port (example.com:8080 to example.com).  I figured I could just change the &amp;#8220;piston:root&amp;#8221; &lt;a href=&quot;http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.1/ch07s02.html&quot;&gt;subversion property&lt;/a&gt; and used svn propedit to do just that.  Unfortunately, on committing the change I could no longer piston update, I was getting a &amp;#8216;command not found&amp;#8217; error from the shell.  This was a bit odd so I dug into the code.  It turns out that there was an extra newline in the piston:root property that was screwing up the svn checkout (the bit after the newline was being treated as a new command by the shell, hence the error).  The solution was to use svn propset rather than svn propedit to set the piston:root property: for some reason svn propedit introduces this unwanted newline, where svn propset doesn&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 18:17:35 +0100</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:0424857d-9f43-46e1-8492-9fb6cbc68016</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-08-01-changing-the-repository-of-code-being-managed-by-piston-an-alternative-to-piston-switch</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Converting Google Code Wiki Content to Html</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve created a little script that allows me to convert documents in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com&quot;&gt;google code&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/support/wiki/WikiSyntax&quot;&gt;wiki format&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The script lives in &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisroos.googlecode.com&quot;&gt;my google code repository&lt;/a&gt;.  Check it out from subversion:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;
svn co http://chrisroos.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/google-wiki-syntax
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The wiki_convertor script takes two arguments.  The first is the wiki file, or directory containing multiple wiki files, and the second is the output directory.  So, to use it to create an html copy of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/doctype/&quot;&gt;google-doctype&lt;/a&gt; wiki content, in my home Sites directory, I&amp;#8217;d use the following command:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;
wiki_convertor.rb ~/Code/third-party/google-doctype/wiki/ ~/Sites/google-doctype/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;This is the first step towards being able to, hopefully, create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portable_Document_Format&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt; copy of the google-doctype content.  Actually, if anyone has any thoughts on this I&amp;#8217;d love to hear them: should I output a different format (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DocBook&quot;&gt;docbook&lt;/a&gt;, for example) or is it easy enough to convert from (x)html to pdf?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The code is covered by quite a few tests but, if peeps find problems converting their own wiki content (for example) then I&amp;#8217;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; There&amp;#8217;s a chance that this becomes less important &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/docreader/#p(google-documentation-reader)s(google-documentation-reader)t(OfflineSupport&quot;&gt;if/when&lt;/a&gt; Google use &lt;a href=&quot;http://gears.google.com/&quot;&gt;gears&lt;/a&gt; in their &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/docreader/#p(google-documentation-reader)s(google-documentation-reader)t(google-documentation-reader&quot;&gt;google docreader&lt;/a&gt; app to allow offline access.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; If you don&amp;#8217;t want to go through this process then you can use a standalone version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://moinmoin.wikiwikiweb.de/&quot;&gt;moinmoin&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/google-doctype/browse_thread/thread/5fe1d26a0afdc4c7&quot;&gt;view your wiki content offline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 21:53:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:2be30c15-b01e-46d7-949c-69218bf4aada</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-07-30-converting-google-code-wiki-content-to-html</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Plans for the my blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a bunch of stuff that I want to do to this blog to simplify things even further. I&amp;#8217;m writing them up to force me to think about them and to see if anyone has any thoughts about my proposals. I&amp;#8217;m sure there&amp;#8217;s lots more I could do but this should keep me busy for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Remove the archive pages.  These are the pages that exist so that you can see every post in a given year, month or day.  I don&amp;#8217;t think I&amp;#8217;ve ever wanted to read these archives on anyone elses site and I can&amp;#8217;t think that anyone would want to do so here.  They are not linked from anywhere on this site (I removed the links when I switched to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/01/23/migration-from-typo-to-a-static-site-is-complete&quot;&gt;static site&lt;/a&gt;) but I know they are still in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.co.uk&quot;&gt;google&lt;/a&gt; index.  I find it annoying if I click on a link to such an archive page as I then have to do a second search, within the page, to find what I&amp;#8217;m looking for.  I guess this might be one of the reasons why google&amp;#8217;s guidelines state that you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/support/webmasters/bin/answer.py?answer=35769&quot;&gt;use robots.txt to prevent crawling of SERPs&lt;/a&gt; (more info from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mattcutts.com/blog/search-results-in-search-results/&quot;&gt;Matt Cutts&lt;/a&gt;).  It&amp;#8217;s for this reason that I removed all paging on the site and redirect anyone that follows a link to a paged page (e.g. articles/page/5) to my &lt;a href=&quot;/contents&quot;&gt;contents&lt;/a&gt; page, explaining why they might not be expecting to see that page.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Change the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; structure to reflect the removal of the archive pages.  My URLs currently look something like /articles/2007/01/01/article-title.  I want to change them to /articles/2007-01-01-title.  This will still allow people, if they really, really wanted, to replicate the functionality of my archive pages by using the google site search functionality (site:blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2007-05 for all articles in May 2007, for example).  Retaining the date in the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; has two (that I can think of) benefits: I find it really useful to get an idea of the age (and possibly relevancy) of a post, and it provides a neat way to generate permalinks.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Remove the tag pages.  For the same reason that I&amp;#8217;ve removed the paged pages and want to remove the archive pages.  I haven&amp;#8217;t been tagging any articles since the switch to a static site and only maintain these pages for the legacy tags.  If I really suffer from the lack of tags then I guess I&amp;#8217;ll just use a tagging service (such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://del.icio.us&quot;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt;) to bookmark my posts with relevant tags.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Remove articles from the url, so that /articles/2007-01-01-blurgh becomes /2007-01-01-blurgh.  It doesn&amp;#8217;t add anything and I&amp;#8217;m not worried about namespace clashes (one thing it could potentially solve).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Move all the content from blog.seagul.co.uk to chrisroos.co.uk/blog.  I want to start using this domain as a starting point for my online identity.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Create chrisroos.co.uk/projects in an attempt to record details of the things that I might class as projects.  This might also solve some of the shortfalls of not having tags (if I did have tags then I might be able to implement this projects idea by using them).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Add the ability to search the site from the site itself (using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/sitesearch/&quot;&gt;google site search&lt;/a&gt; or similar). I sometimes find the need to search my own site and having to do site:blog.seagul.co.uk keywords can become frustrating.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Revisit previous articles and add meta descriptions to their pages.  This is the text that google displays in their &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Search_engine_results_page&quot;&gt;SERPs&lt;/a&gt; and is generally useful as an overview of the content.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Add the permalink of each post in the form of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://microformats.org/wiki/rel-bookmark&quot;&gt;link rel=bookmark&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Add link tags (prev, next, home?) to describe the &lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintoaccessibility.org/day_9_providing_additional_navigation_aids.html&quot;&gt;relationship between posts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Remove the embedded syntax highlighting from some of the posts, preferring, instead, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/syntaxhighlighter/&quot;&gt;javascript solution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Attempt to clear up any broken links in the content.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; A guiding principle behind the removal of composite pages (tags, archives and paged pages) is that a post should only appear at one &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; on this site.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; I believe there may be benefits of the archive and tag pages in that they allow search engines to effectively spider all your content. I&amp;#8217;m fairly happy that my contents page and sitemap mean that I&amp;#8217;m covered in this respect.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;Steps required to move towards the architecture (URL) changes&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noindex&quot;&gt;noindex&lt;/a&gt; to all the archive pages, and optionally request their removal, so that they disappear from the search engine indexes.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Add noindex to all the tag pages, and optionally request their removal, so that they disappear from the search engine indexes.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Possibly redirect requests for archive pages to a google search that provides the same functionality.  Alternatively redirect them to my contents page.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Redirect requests for tag pages to my contents page.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Redirect all requests for URLs that start with /articles to the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; without /articles.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Redirect all requests for URLs on the blog.seagul.co.uk domain to chrisroos.co.uk/blog.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 21:24:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:20c1637a-a5ae-43e7-839b-c405a3863fcd</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-07-30-plans-for-the-my-blog</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Asking South Eastern about the high speed trains</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I noticed, having already written everything below, that there&amp;#8217;s actually quite a lot of information about the high speed proposals on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southeastern_(train_operating_company)#Future_expansion&quot;&gt;South Eastern&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikipedia.org/&quot;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s been lots of speculation about the new high speed trains that are going to decrease journey times from, parts of, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kent&quot;&gt;Kent&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London&quot;&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;.  The south eastern site is very sparse on the details of these new services so I thought I&amp;#8217;d email them to ask for more details: I&amp;#8217;m specifically interested in journey times from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramsgate&quot;&gt;Ramsgate&lt;/a&gt; to London.  I shouldn&amp;#8217;t be surprised, but their answer contains essentially no information.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I mentioned to a signal man friend at the weekend and he was of the impression that they&amp;#8217;d be running fast services direct from Ramsgate to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_Pancras_railway_station&quot;&gt;St Pancras&lt;/a&gt; and from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canterbury&quot;&gt;Canterbury&lt;/a&gt; to St Pancras.  I&amp;#8217;ll guess we&amp;#8217;ll just have to wait a year or so to find out what they&amp;#8217;re actually going to do.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;My email (submitted through their &lt;a href=&quot;http://southeasternrailway.co.uk/contact.php&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;email&quot;&gt;
Hi,

	&lt;p&gt;I wonder if you’d be able to let me know your plans for services between Ramsgate and London when the new high speed trains are introduced?  Although there’s been a great deal of speculation about a high speed service between Ramsgate and St Pancras, I’ve never seen anything concrete.  Indeed, from what I’ve read so far, I’m guessing that there won’t be a direct high speed link between Ramsgate and London (I’d love to hear otherwise though).  Rather, I suspect that it’ll be possible to get a traditional train from Ramsgate to Ashford and then to join a high speed train to St Pancras (so the journey time will be about 77 minutes on the train with a change at Ashford).  Is this the plan?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I also wonder if you might shed some light on the proposed price increases to use the new high speed service?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Cheers, and I look forward to a reply,&lt;/p&gt;


Chris
&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;And their response (&lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/chrisjroos/2688362103/&quot;&gt;original&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/chrisjroos/2688361813/&quot;&gt;page 2&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
Ref: 329980 / 99573

	&lt;p&gt;16 July 2008&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr Roos,&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HS1&lt;/span&gt; services&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your website comment that we received on 10 July 2008, regarding the high speed services that will commence in 2009.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;We will be introducing services on &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HS1&lt;/span&gt; (the new name for the Channel Tunnel Rail Link) from December 2009 and the timetable for our existing ‘classic’ routes will be re-drawn completely.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Services using &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HS1&lt;/span&gt; will go to London&amp;#8217;s St Pancras station and journey times from places like Ashford, Folkestone, Canterbury, Ramsgate and Dover will be significantly reduced. We understand that many people are keen to know exactly what the timetable and fares will be, but I hope you will understand that this is still at the planning stage and the details are yet to be finalised.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The Department for Transport (DfT) has set out the overarching specification for the timetable that we will deliver. We are currently reviewing this specification and have started to test the journey times with the first of the new trains. Once we are able to share the detail of the timetable we will communicate it to customers via our website and the media. As with any other timetable change, we will be consulting with Passenger Focus and London TravelWatch, the two main passenger watchdogs before the timetable is introduced. So if a strong economic argument for a particular service can be demonstrated, and the railway industry can accommodate it, we would present a business case to the DtT to support its introduction.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;ln the meantime, our website does have some details about the proposed journey times and routes. This can be located on our homepage by clicking on &amp;#8220;High Speed Services&amp;#8221; on the left hand side and then &amp;#8220;Frequency of trains&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Thank you for taking the time to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Russell L. D&amp;#8217;Eath&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Customer Relations Ofticer&lt;/p&gt;


Southeastern
&lt;/div&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 22:15:25 +0100</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:e31cf39d-afba-42b3-971c-3e84c0fc7b3a</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-07-21-asking-south-eastern-about-the-high-speed-trains</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Asking South Eastern about their crappy seats</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I regularly travel on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://southeasternrailway.co.uk/&quot;&gt;South Eastern&lt;/a&gt; service from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterloo_East_railway_station&quot;&gt;Waterloo East&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramsgate&quot;&gt;Ramsgate&lt;/a&gt;.  The train splits at &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashford_International&quot;&gt;Ashford&lt;/a&gt; and I end up having to sit in the shitty commuter seats for the last 45 minutes (or so) of the journey.  I emailed South Eastern to ask if they couldn&amp;#8217;t reconfigure the train so that, of the eight cars that go to Dover, four could have commuter seats and four could have real seats.  They could then send the other four cars, with real seats, to Ramsgate.  I don&amp;#8217;t think I have the original email that I sent (feedback forms in general suffer from the problem that the sender doesn&amp;#8217;t retain a copy of what&amp;#8217;s been sent) but their reply is below (&lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/chrisjroos/2688362397/&quot;&gt;original here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
Ref: 329980 / 93994

	&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr Roos&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Formation of 17.59 Waterloo East to Ramsgate Service&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your email of 2nd May&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I am sorry that you have found the seating on the rear four carriages of the above service to be uncomfortable. These are the higher density carriages that have 2+3 seating across the coach, rather than 2+2 seating, and are intended to deal with the heavy demand we face during the busy peak periods. We know that everyone would prefer all our trains to have 2+2 seating throughout. However, we have to utilise the higher density seating layout in order to provide enough seats for our London commuters.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;For a number of operational factors (for example, rolling stock maintenance), it is difficult to locate a set of four higher density carriages in the middle of a twelve-coach train, where the front and rear portions are formed of 2+2 seating. The usual procedure is to have four or eight carriages which are the same, and to have an additonai four carriages of either the higher density or 2+2 rolling stock. In addition to this, we have to look at the wider picture and consider what is needed for later services or on the following morning (as a rule, it is not possible to &amp;#8220;mix-and-match&amp;#8221; rolling stock to it each journey).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, it is unlikely that we will be able to make the change that to have requested. Thank you, however, for sharing your concerns with us. Passenger feedback, whether good or bad, is always appreciated so that we can continue to improve on the service we offer, and I hope you can be reassured that we take all issues very seriously.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;David Eustace&lt;/p&gt;


Southeastern Customer Services
&lt;/div&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 21:08:55 +0100</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:4c56508e-363a-4446-8526-470ee95be326</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-07-21-asking-south-eastern-about-their-crappy-seats</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Source Optical Character Recognition (OCR) on the Mac</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently received a letter reply to an enquiry I made to &lt;a href=&quot;http://southeasternrailway.co.uk/&quot;&gt;South Eastern Trains&lt;/a&gt;.  I wanted to make the text available (I don&amp;#8217;t like reading text in images) but didn&amp;#8217;t want to type it all out.  Having scanned it in, I looked around for some &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_character_recognition&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OCR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; software, for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/mac/&quot;&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, that would extract the text for me.  Through the (relatively large amount of) search result noise, I managed to find a reference to &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/tesseract-ocr/&quot;&gt;tesseract&lt;/a&gt;.  Installing from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macports.org/&quot;&gt;Mac Ports&lt;/a&gt; was easy but actually getting useful output was slightly tricker.  I was trying to extract the text from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/chrisjroos/2688362397/&quot;&gt;this letter&lt;/a&gt; but kept getting garbled output.  I tried a few things before stumbling across &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/OCR&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; that suggests making the image greyscale and ensuring that the extension is .tif (not .tiff).  I duly complied, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://seashore.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;Seashore&lt;/a&gt; to convert the image to greyscale, and tried again.  This time the text was extracted perfectly (even the addresses, that appear in two columns, were extracted correctly).&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 14:04:56 +0100</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:19495a24-8ef5-4c1a-aab1-45d38a8ed548</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-07-21-open-source-optical-character-recognition-ocr-on-the-mac</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pwdhash Widget</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://pwdhash.com&quot;&gt;pwdhash&lt;/a&gt; for ages.  Apart from some pathetic sites that impose password limitations (less than x characters, or no &amp;#8216;strange&amp;#8217; characters), I&amp;#8217;ve used it on every site I&amp;#8217;ve signed up to.  This has started to change recently as more sites offer a client application that sits alongside the online app (&lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com&quot;&gt;flickr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://last.fm&quot;&gt;last.fm&lt;/a&gt; come to mind): It&amp;#8217;s a pain to visit pwdhash.com every time I need to generate a password for an offline app.  So, I decided to have a stab at creating a dashboard widget to generate password hashes.  I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/tools/dashcode/&quot;&gt;dashcode&lt;/a&gt; (which makes this stuff &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; easy) and got something knocked up, in about an hour, on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/chrisroos/statuses/812954936&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/a&gt;.  The fact that pwdhash.com is already composed of html and javascript helped just a bit too&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if it sounds useful feel then free to download it &lt;a href=&quot;/files/pwdhash.zip&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 21:58:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:8b08900d-3772-466f-8da4-05cb81f67e40</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://chrisroos.co.uk/blog/2008-05-19-pwdhash-widget</link>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

