<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/stylesheets/rss.css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>deferred until inspiration hits</title>
    <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>

    <description></description>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another project - Public Swimming Pools in the UK</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not content with already having a &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2008/02/18/what-ive-been-up-to-projects-and-ideas&quot;&gt;bunch of unfinished projects&lt;/a&gt; I thought I&amp;#8217;d embark upon another.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve struggled in the past to find public swimming pools that I can use when staying in London.  I&amp;#8217;ve searched on multiple occasions and never really found anything useful so figured there was probably a gap waiting to be filled.  Interestingly, I think that someone in or around the government must realise this too.  A search, on google, for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=uk+public+swimming+pools&quot;&gt;uk public swimming pools&lt;/a&gt; results in an &lt;a href=&quot;http://adwords.google.com&quot;&gt;Adword&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://direct.gov.uk&quot;&gt;DirectGov&lt;/a&gt; that takes you to a page promoting the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.activeplaces.com&quot;&gt;Active Places&lt;/a&gt; website.  This website allows you to search for leisure facilities by postcode or by clicking around a map.  As noted in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://del.icio.us/chrisjroos/url/0a078da5074a6c759210508c0bc6a60e&quot;&gt;del.icio.us note&lt;/a&gt;, I think this could be a valuable site but the current implementation is very very poor: Both from a usability and search engine friendly point of view (I can&amp;#8217;t help but wonder, as it appears to be a Government funded project, through Sport England, how much money has been spent on it).  One last point about the site is that it appears to include data about pools that can&amp;#8217;t actually be used by members of the public (a pool belonging to a local private school appears when searching for pools near home).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;According to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theyworkforyou.com/wrans/?id=2008-03-10b.192802.h&quot;&gt;parliamentary question&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.culture.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;department for Culture, Media and Sport&lt;/a&gt; know the number and type of pools opened and closed since 2004: actually, I&amp;#8217;ve just noticed that they appear to rely on the Active Places database.  There&amp;#8217;s an email address (actually, a Sport England address) on the Active Places website that I&amp;#8217;m going to use to see if I can get hold of this data.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The initial, and most basic, site will just list all the public swimming pools and, I&amp;#8217;m hoping this is pretty easy with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/apis/maps/&quot;&gt;Google Maps &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, allow you to search for one by location.  As, and indeed if, the site evolves, I&amp;#8217;d like to get lots more useful information about these pools up: I&amp;#8217;m hoping that allowing users to comment will reveal useful info about the best times to visit depending on what you&amp;#8217;re trying to get out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 14:18:43 +0100</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:81049870-4a70-495f-8774-ef1ca3d2f15f</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/03/31/another-project-public-swimming-pools-in-the-uk</link>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reference Trackback Server implementation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To aid my development of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/03/04/version-0-2-of-the-del-icio-us-trackback-extension&quot;&gt;del.icio.us trackbacks firefox extension&lt;/a&gt; I created a reference &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trackback&quot;&gt;trackback&lt;/a&gt; server implementation based on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sixapart.com/pronet/docs/trackback_spec&quot;&gt;trackback specification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s written in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ruby-lang.org&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mongrel.rubyforge.org/&quot;&gt;Mongrel&lt;/a&gt; handler and stores the trackbacks serialized to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YAML&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;YAML&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the filesystem.  The code is over in &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/chrisroos/&quot;&gt;my google code repository&lt;/a&gt; (no direct link as I plan to move the trackback-server from its current home in /trunk/scratch to /trunk/www/trackbacks.seagul.co.uk).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;On the off-chance that someone else might find it useful I&amp;#8217;m currently hosting it at &lt;a href=&quot;http://trackbacks.seagul.co.uk&quot;&gt;http://trackbacks.seagul.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.  You might use it to see the del.icio.us trackbacks extension in action or to test the sending of trackbacks from your blog (the trackback &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;http://trackbacks.seagul.co.uk/trackback&quot;&gt;http://trackbacks.seagul.co.uk/trackback&lt;/a&gt;).  Or, you could just play with it using &lt;a href=&quot;http://curl.haxx.se&quot;&gt;curl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;typocode&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;typocode_default&quot;&gt;# Let's just try to GET the trackback URL
$ curl http://trackbacks.seagul.co.uk/trackback
&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot; encoding=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;response&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;error&amp;gt;1&amp;lt;/error&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;message&amp;gt;Http Method MUST be POST&amp;lt;/message&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/response&amp;gt;

# OK, so we'll POST to the trackback URL
$ curl http://trackbacks.seagul.co.uk/trackback -X&amp;quot;POST&amp;quot;
&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot; encoding=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;response&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;error&amp;gt;1&amp;lt;/error&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;message&amp;gt;Content-Type MUST be 'application/x-www-form-urlencoded' with OPTIONAL character encoding&amp;lt;/message&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/response&amp;gt;

# Posting with the correct Content-Type
$ curl http://trackbacks.seagul.co.uk/trackback -X&amp;quot;POST&amp;quot; -H&amp;quot;Content-Type: application/x-wencoded&amp;quot;
&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot; encoding=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;response&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;error&amp;gt;1&amp;lt;/error&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;message&amp;gt;You MUST send the URL of your post (permalink) that mentions this post.&amp;lt;/message&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/response&amp;gt;

# Post with the correct Content-Type and the required URL parameter to actually have a trackback created on the server
$ curl http://trackbacks.seagul.co.uk/trackback -X&amp;quot;POST&amp;quot; -H&amp;quot;Content-Type: application/x-wencoded&amp;quot; -d&amp;quot;url=http://example.com&amp;quot;
&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot; encoding=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;response&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;error&amp;gt;0&amp;lt;/error&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/response&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 06:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:d9caacb2-2920-4ccd-ac3f-f2154258c400</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/03/29/reference-trackback-server-implementation</link>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Files hosted on Google Groups cannot be opened in Safari (or Internet Explorer)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I noticed a little while ago that opening a, &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com&quot;&gt;Google Groups&lt;/a&gt; hosted, file in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/safari/&quot;&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt; didn&amp;#8217;t work.  I have a file at &lt;a href=&quot;http://delicious-trackbacks.googlegroups.com/web/installation.html&quot;&gt;http://delicious-trackbacks.googlegroups.com/web/installation.html&lt;/a&gt; that you can try out if you&amp;#8217;re so inclined.  Requests for that file result in a page being rendered in Firefox but not in Safari or Internet Explorer (6 at least).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://interblah.net/&quot;&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; noticed that requests for these hosted files were resulting in a 302 response, as we can see from this &lt;a href=&quot;http://curl.haxx.se/&quot;&gt;curl&lt;/a&gt; output.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;typocode&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;typocode_default&quot;&gt;curl &amp;quot;http://delicious-trackbacks.googlegroups.com/web/installation.html&amp;quot; -v -X&amp;quot;HEAD&amp;quot;

&amp;lt; HTTP/1.1 302 Moved Temporarily
&amp;lt; Content-Type: text/html; charset=UTF-8
&amp;lt; Content-Length: 0
&amp;lt; Cache-control: private
&amp;lt; Server: GFE/1.3
&amp;lt; Date: Fri, 28 Mar 2008 19:55:58 GMT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The response also includes a body that contains a link to the actual file you want with some kind of key in the querystring.  Interestingly the response doesn&amp;#8217;t return a Location header.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616-sec10.html#sec10.3.3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; specification&lt;/a&gt; states the following:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The temporary &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URI SHOULD&lt;/span&gt; be given by the Location field in the response. Unless the request method was &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HEAD&lt;/span&gt;, the entity of the response &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SHOULD&lt;/span&gt; contain a short hypertext note with a hyperlink to the new &lt;acronym title=&quot;s&quot;&gt;URI&lt;/acronym&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So, it looks like Google are sending a valid response according to the spec (although I&amp;#8217;m not sure whether they&amp;#8217;re intentionally leaving the Location header out) but that Safari and Internet Explorer are unable to deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I found an existing report of &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.webkit.org/show_bug.cgi?id=15822&quot;&gt;the bug&lt;/a&gt; over at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://webkit.org/&quot;&gt;webkit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.webkit.org/&quot;&gt;bug tracker&lt;/a&gt; and added this information to it.  I also sent a &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/Is-Something-Broken/browse_thread/thread/9e9a51c2b6841c8f/28088b462550858e#28088b462550858e&quot;&gt;message&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/Google-Groups-Guide&quot;&gt;Google Groups: Is Something Broken&lt;/a&gt; group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 06:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:97bcff83-94f1-4808-a723-2769584d257a</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/03/29/files-hosted-on-google-groups-cannot-be-opened-in-safari-or-internet-explorer</link>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Version Control Commit Note Best Practice (or not, you decide)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my own opinion but it has evolved from the need to dig back into past commit notes &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;.  The lazy approach to writing commit notes is just to explain what&amp;#8217;s in the changeset (much like a code comment that says &amp;#8220;set x to 1&amp;#8221;):  It&amp;#8217;s exactly what I used to write (and still do if I&amp;#8217;m not concentrating).  The more useful approach is to explain why the changeset is there.  I can take two of my own commit notes as examples.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h2&gt;Useless commit note&lt;/h2&gt;


	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Capistrano deploy:setup should generate apache proxy cluster configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This is a fairly useless commit note: If I was to come back to this (as I did today when looking at it) I would have no idea what I was trying to achieve.  Why should the config be generated at setup and not at some other point in the deploy process?  If I&amp;#8217;d spent an extra 30 seconds writing the note in the first place I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have to try to work out what I was trying to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h2&gt;More useful commit note&lt;/h2&gt;


	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;This isn't a card but _has_ been bugging me for a long time. You can now click on the &lt;product_type&gt; in the 'Top 3 &lt;product_type&gt;' headings on super category pages to visit that product type. Oh, I also made them h2s as having multiple h1s on a page just doesn't make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This is a much more useful (imho) comment.  If at some point in the future we want to know why the &amp;#8216;top 3 product types&amp;#8217; is now a link, we can come back to the note and see that it was because I, personally, was fed up of it not being so.  I also explain why I&amp;#8217;ve changed the heading from a h1 to h2 (although that comment could be open to interpretation: why doesn&amp;#8217;t it make sense?).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This all ties into submitting small checkins that are only doing one thing, but I might try to give some examples of that separately.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Anyone else have any thoughts or alternative approaches?&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 19:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:ae997b7a-4abf-4c07-bdbb-082eb3e64401</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/03/28/version-control-commit-note-best-practice-or-not-you-decide</link>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Version 0.2 of the del.icio.us trackback extension</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got round to compiling the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/02/04/sending-trackbacks-to-the-sites-that-you-bookmark-in-del-icio-us&quot;&gt;del.icio.us trackback extension&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about a while back.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;You can install it from the installation.html&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; page on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/delicious-trackbacks&quot;&gt;del.icio.us trackbacks google group&lt;/a&gt;.  Feel free to use that group to post any questions you have too.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Current features:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Scans the html of the page you&amp;#8217;re bookmarking looking for a link (anchor) with a rel attribute whose value is trackback.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Sends a request to the trackback &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URI&lt;/span&gt; if it was found.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Records (by adding the &amp;#8216;dtb-sent&amp;#8217; tag) the sending of the trackback so that we can avoid sending multiple trackbacks to the same site.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Records the success (&amp;#8216;dtb-success&amp;#8217; tag) or failure (&amp;#8216;dtb-failure&amp;#8217;) of the trackback request.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s all for now.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I don&amp;#8217;t appear to be able to link directly to that page which is a bit odd.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:d1b7bcd5-eed9-410e-8d2f-3232aca73d04</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/03/04/version-0-2-of-the-del-icio-us-trackback-extension</link>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>National Rail Train Times by SMS (again)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2007/07/24/train-times-by-sms-or-improving-national-rail-enquiries&quot;&gt;hacked&lt;/a&gt; a simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Short_message_service&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; interface onto the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalrail.co.uk/&quot;&gt;national rail enquiries&lt;/a&gt; website.  It turned out to be more gimmicky than functional and I left it to die.  Over the past couple of weeks I&amp;#8217;ve found myself, once again, in need of such a service and so spent a couple of hours last night reviving it: making it work, making it simpler and tidying the code.  The previous interface required the source station and destination station as well as the date and time of travel.  The format was very strict (requiring you to use the unique three digit station codes) and, as I found, overly complex (I could never remember what it was).  All I really wanted to do was specify the source and destination stations and get a list of the next few departures/arrival times.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The new interface is simply in the format of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOURCE&lt;/span&gt;_STATION to &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DESTINATION&lt;/span&gt;_STATION.  So, to find the next few trains from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramsgate_railway_station&quot;&gt;Ramsgate&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterloo_East_railway_station&quot;&gt;London Waterloo East&lt;/a&gt; we can send the following &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.twitter.com/index.php?pg=kb.page&amp;#38;id=15&quot;&gt;direct message&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/natrailenq&quot;&gt;natrailenq&lt;/a&gt; user on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;typocode&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;typocode_default&quot;&gt;d natrailenq ramsgate to london waterloo east&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Although you can now use the full station name it will only, currently, work if you know the exact name of the station (so, waterloo east wouldn&amp;#8217;t work in that above example, but london waterloo east will).  It will still work if you supply the three digit station code.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;In order to use this service, you will need to create a twitter account, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/help/follow&quot;&gt;follow&lt;/a&gt; the natrailenq user and enable &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; notifications from natrailenq.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:6f82d1cd-59c4-414f-8b35-a3a1d5160e3e</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/02/28/national-rail-train-times-by-sms-again</link>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tagging my del.icio.us bookmarks with the domain of the URL that I'm bookmarking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve created another &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.com/firefox&quot;&gt;firefox&lt;/a&gt; extension that builds on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://del.icio.us&quot;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/3615&quot;&gt;extension&lt;/a&gt;.  This one finds the domain of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; you&amp;#8217;re bookmarking and adds it as a tag to your bookmark.  It&amp;#8217;s basically just a copy of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2007/12/18/extracting-my-del-icio-us-permalinks-functionality-into-its-own-firefox-extension&quot;&gt;del.icio.us permalinks extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;To install this extension head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/delicious-domain-tags&quot;&gt;delicious domain tags google group&lt;/a&gt; and visit the installation page (I don&amp;#8217;t seem to be able to link directly to it for some reason).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I came across an interesting problem when trying to get both this and the del.icio.us permalinks extension working together.  Both of the extensions modify the onload attribute of the add bookmark dialog.  When I only had the del.icio.us permalinks extension I was hardcoding the onload attribute to call my function (deliciousPermalinks.addPermalinkTag()) and the original function (yAddBookMark.init()).  This approach fell down as soon as I had two extensions trying to modify the onload attribute: I didn&amp;#8217;t know which extension would be loaded first and therefore one was always overwriting the other.  I&amp;#8217;m sure there&amp;#8217;s a nice way to do this but I hacked together a noddy initialisation script that finds the existing value of the onload attribute and adds to it with the relevant function.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;typocode&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;typocode_default&quot;&gt;var yAddBookmarkDialog = document.getElementById('dlg_AddYBookMark');
var yAddBookmarkOnload = yAddBookmarkDialog.getAttribute('onload');
var onload = 'deliciousPermalinks.addPermalinkTag()';
yAddBookmarkDialog.setAttribute('onload', [yAddBookmarkOnload, onload].join(';'))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I reference this script in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XUL&quot;&gt;xul&lt;/a&gt; file which causes it to be evaluated at (I guess) browser start time and the onload event to be modified correctly.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve updated the del.icio.us permalinks extension too but I think you&amp;#8217;ll need to remove and re-add it again from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/delicious-permalinks/files&quot;&gt;installation page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 08:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:0965ddb3-1309-4dc8-a04f-297cf892aa75</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/02/26/tagging-my-del-icio-us-bookmarks-with-the-domain-of-the-url-that-im-bookmarking</link>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've been up to - Projects and Ideas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been a bit quiet on the blogging front (to be fair, I&amp;#8217;ve always been a bit slack) but I think it&amp;#8217;s for good reason: I&amp;#8217;ve re-discovered a love for programming, and in particular, creating things that I (and hopefully others) find useful.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So, as a bit of an update, and a bit of a reminder for me, I thought I&amp;#8217;d list all the things I&amp;#8217;m either working on or thinking about.  Feel free to ask questions in the comments or by emailing me (chris at this domain).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h2&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;Atom (like &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt;) feed for thisiskent news content&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m interested in reading news articles from the local area but the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisiskent.co.uk&quot;&gt;thisiskent website&lt;/a&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t provide a feed for me to subscribe to.  I&amp;#8217;ve created a little project that scrapes the news content from that site and produces a feed.  The feed is currently at &lt;a href=&quot;http://seagul.co.uk/thisiskent-thanet.atom&quot;&gt;http://seagul.co.uk/thisiskent-thanet.atom&lt;/a&gt; but will possibly move in the future.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;The Local Paper&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I wanted to give each article, in our local papers, a permalink so that people had a way to reference an article they were talking about.  I&amp;#8217;ve started building the site over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://the-local-paper.co.uk&quot;&gt;http://the-local-paper.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.  There&amp;#8217;s a long way to go but I really wanted to start getting some content up so that I had more incentive to continue.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/06/01/an-open-letter-to-my-local-newspapers&quot;&gt;An open letter to my local newspapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;Sending trackbacks to pages that I bookmark in &lt;a href=&quot;http://del.icio.us&quot;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I asked for this a while back in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/ydn-delicious/message/1447&quot;&gt;del.icio.us group&lt;/a&gt;.  It occurred to me that I could add the functionality myself to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/3615&quot;&gt;del.icio.us firefox extension&lt;/a&gt;, so I did.  It&amp;#8217;s more of a proof of concept at the moment but you can follow &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2008/02/04/sending-trackbacks-to-the-sites-that-you-bookmark-in-del-icio-us&quot;&gt;these instructions&lt;/a&gt; if you wish to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2008/02/04/sending-trackbacks-to-the-sites-that-you-bookmark-in-del-icio-us&quot;&gt;Sending trackbacks to the sites that you bookmark in del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;Adding &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permalink&quot;&gt;permalinks&lt;/a&gt; to del.icio.us bookmarks&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This was the precursor to the trackbacks project above.  I&amp;#8217;ve created a firefox extension that, building on the del.icio.us extension, adds a &amp;#8216;permalink tag&amp;#8217; to each bookmark you create.  You can read more &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/12/18/extracting-my-del-icio-us-permalinks-functionality-into-its-own-firefox-extension&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://delicious-permalinks.googlegroups.com/web/installation.html&quot;&gt;installation page&lt;/a&gt; to install the extension.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/12/18/extracting-my-del-icio-us-permalinks-functionality-into-its-own-firefox-extension&quot;&gt;Extracting my del.icio.us permalinks functionality into its own firefox extension&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/09/29/commenting-on-my-del-icio-us-bookmarks&quot;&gt;Commenting on my del.icio.us bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/09/05/patching-the-del-icio-us-firefox-extension-to-add-permalinks&quot;&gt;Patching the del.icio.us firefox extension to add permalinks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/09/04/permalinks-for-del-icio-us-bookmarks-posts&quot; title=&quot;posts&quot;&gt;Permalinks for del.icio.us bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;Some blogging software&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I decided that I really didn&amp;#8217;t need the overhead of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typosphere.org/&quot;&gt;typo&lt;/a&gt; to produce what is essentially a static site.  The result is some software that produces the website that you&amp;#8217;re reading now.  I actually need to get some work done on this because I&amp;#8217;m currently in a position where it&amp;#8217;s harder for me to add content now than it used to be with typo.  D&amp;#8217;oh.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2008/01/23/migration-from-typo-to-a-static-site-is-complete&quot;&gt;Migration from typo to a static site is complete&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2008/01/23/migrating-this-blog-from-typo-to-a-static-site&quot;&gt;Migrating this blog from Typo to a static site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;An &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; service to lookup train information&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve built a service on top of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to request departure information.  This is actually live now (read the &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/07/24/train-times-by-sms-or-improving-national-rail-enquiries&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;) but could be a lot more useful.  I&amp;#8217;ve found that my main use case is to find the next few trains from a specific station within the next half hour or so &amp;#8211; I&amp;#8217;m hoping to make the interface better suit this need.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/07/24/train-times-by-sms-or-improving-national-rail-enquiries&quot; title=&quot;or, improving National Rail Enquiries&quot;&gt;Train times by &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;Software to interface with banking websites and download/convert the data to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ofx.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OFX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (for upload to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wesabe.com&quot;&gt;wesabe&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;A while back, I got quite addicted to using wesabe in an attempt to manage my finances (as it happens I&amp;#8217;ve been very slack on this front too &amp;#8211; managing money is just boring).  I wrote some scripts to download data from my banks&amp;#8217; websites and additionally to convert that data to &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OFX&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/06/23/automatically-downloading-my-ing-direct-transactions&quot;&gt;Automatically downloading my Ing Direct transactions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/06/23/automatically-download-egg-credit-card-transactions&quot;&gt;Automatically download egg credit card transactions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/05/14/automatically-downloading-my-recent-transactions-from-lloyds-tsb&quot;&gt;Automatically downloading my recent transactions from Lloyds &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TSB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/05/04/automatically-downloading-my-most-recent-hsbc-transactions&quot;&gt;Automatically downloading my most recent Hsbc transactions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/04/01/converting-egg-credit-card-statements-to-ofx-for-upload-to-wesabe&quot; title=&quot;for upload to wesabe&quot;&gt;Converting Egg Credit Card Statements to Ofx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;A ruby implementation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pwdhash.com&quot;&gt;pwdhash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I wanted a command line version of the pwdhash tool.  I knocked up a ruby implementation but haven&amp;#8217;t really got round to making it command line friendly.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/04/11/getting-to-grips-with-pwdhash&quot;&gt;Getting to grips with pwdhash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;A web service that converts a UK postcode to Latitude/Longitude&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It currently lives at &lt;a href=&quot;http://seagul.co.uk/postcodes&quot;&gt;http://seagul.co.uk/postcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/07/13/web-service-to-convert-uk-postcodes-outcode-to-latitude-and-longitude&quot;&gt;Web service to convert UK Postcodes (outcode) to Latitude and Longitude&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/04/03/obtaining-latitude-longitude-for-uk-postcodes&quot;&gt;Obtaining latitude/longitude for UK postcodes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h2&gt;Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;A del.icio.us extension that mines del.icio.us (and magnolia etc) to find similar sites to those that I&amp;#8217;m looking at&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I did a fair bit of investigation into this, although I&amp;#8217;m not sure any of it is of any real use.  I was working on the theory that if the page I&amp;#8217;m looking at is tagged with, for example, &amp;#8216;train&amp;#8217;, &amp;#8216;uk&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;travel&amp;#8217; then other pages tagged in the same way would probably also be of interest.  Check the &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisroos.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/delicious_similar_sites&quot;&gt;delicious_similar_sites&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisroos.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/delicious-sidebar&quot;&gt;delicious-sidebar&lt;/a&gt; projects to check my progress.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/10/03/finding-similar-sites-by-mining-the-del-icio-us-data&quot;&gt;Finding similar sites by mining the del.icio.us data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;A hosted &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trackback&quot;&gt;trackback&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pingback&quot;&gt;pingback&lt;/a&gt; service&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m thinking of something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disqus.com&quot;&gt;disqus&lt;/a&gt; (hosted comments service) but for trackbacks/pingbacks.  I did find a site called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trackbackr.com&quot;&gt;trackbackr&lt;/a&gt; that would appear to offer something similar but I haven&amp;#8217;t looked into it in any detail.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;A hosted redirection service&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I want an easy way to create short/friendly URLs for a domain that I own.  I&amp;#8217;ve started exploring the possibility of a RESTful service to do just this.  There&amp;#8217;s some initial code over on &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisroos.co.uk/code/mongrel-redirection&quot;&gt;google code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/12/07/more-on-those-friendly-urls&quot;&gt;More on those friendly URLs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/11/27/short-human-friendly-permalinks&quot;&gt;Short, Human friendly, Permalinks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;A mobile friendly version of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalrail.co.uk&quot;&gt;National Rail Enquiries&lt;/a&gt; website&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I need to check whether this is already covered by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.traintimes.org.uk&quot;&gt;accessible national rails&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;An &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; alert with train information&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;For three mornings a week, I get a regular train.  I&amp;#8217;d like to receive a text message, half an hour (or so) before I leave house, that tells me whether the train is running on time.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;A receipt tagging application (del.icio.us for receipts)&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Until recently I had a lot of receipts stored on my email server.  This didn&amp;#8217;t feel like the right place for them so I&amp;#8217;ve placed them all on my laptop, in a folder that gets backed up to &lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/s3&quot;&gt;Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt; with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jungledisk.com&quot;&gt;jungledisk&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;#8217;d like to be able to tag these receipts to make retrieval easier.  Ooh, I just had a thought &amp;#8211; I wonder if I could just bookmark their &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;S3 URL&lt;/span&gt; in del.icio.us&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;Some software to track my unsubscriptions&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Marketing emails annoy me.  I almost certainly don&amp;#8217;t want them.  More importantly, when I state that I don&amp;#8217;t want them, I want to have my wishes respected.  I knew that I was getting emails from companies that I&amp;#8217;d unsubscribed from and wanted to track the offenders.  I&amp;#8217;ve been using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stikipad.com&quot;&gt;stikipad&lt;/a&gt; wiki to do this but it&amp;#8217;s not exactly ideal.  I&amp;#8217;d like a service that will collect these emails (I&amp;#8217;m thinking that I&amp;#8217;ll forward them straight there) and report on those naughty companies that keep spamming me.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/10/31/naughty-spammy-tesco-entertainment&quot;&gt;Naughty spammy Tesco Entertainment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/09/21/companies-you-must-make-it-simple-for-me-to-unsubscribe-from-your-marketing-shite&quot;&gt;Companies. You must make it simple for me to unsubscribe from your marketing shite&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/03/16/orange-orange-orange&quot;&gt;Orange, orange, orange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;A firefox extension/&lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/748&quot;&gt;greasemonkey&lt;/a&gt; script to determine the canonical &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; of a resource&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;At one stage I was trying to use del.icio.us to manage the stuff I had for sale on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ebay.co.uk&quot;&gt;ebay&lt;/a&gt;.  Unfortunately, ebay is a bit naughty with their URLs (the same item for sale is available at different URLs) which meant I could end up bookmarking one &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; and then not find my bookmark notes again &amp;#8211; even though I knew I was looking at the same item.  I figure that we could maintain a list of rules that allow you to turn any &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; into its canonical version.  This wouldn&amp;#8217;t be ebay specific.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Related posts: &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2007/12/14/web-pages-should-specify-their-canonical-url-permalink&quot; title=&quot;permalink&quot;&gt;Web pages should specify their canonical &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;A website with lots of info about swimming pools&lt;/h3&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve found it quite hard to find swimming pools close to work in the past.  I&amp;#8217;d like a site that has a map of all swimming pools in the local area along with info (opening times, costs) and reviews of those pools (when&amp;#8217;s a good time to go).&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 10:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:cf1cb765-edb9-4db9-aab3-08e439b97047</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/02/18/what-ive-been-up-to-projects-and-ideas</link>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Atom (like RSS) feeds for thisiskent.co.uk news stories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve only recently discovered that thisiskent.co.uk (the website of three of our local newspapers) place their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisiskent.co.uk/displayNode.jsp?nodeId=250478&amp;#38;command=newPage&quot;&gt;news content&lt;/a&gt; online.  Unfortunately they&amp;#8217;ve neglected to provide &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atom_%28standard%29&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; feeds which means that I don&amp;#8217;t get to see it (visiting websites is soooo old school).  As I&amp;#8217;m kinda interested in reading this news, I&amp;#8217;ve put something together that creates a feed from their news articles.  The feed currently lives at http://seagul.co.uk/thisiskent-thanet.atom although this will probably move in the future.  Feel free to subscribe to the feed and please leave comments if it&amp;#8217;s not working for you.  I&amp;#8217;m currently only interested in the Thanet news section but I&amp;#8217;d be happy to produce a feed for other areas if people are interested.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The code&amp;#8217;s over on &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisroos.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/thisis-rss/&quot;&gt;google code&lt;/a&gt; if you want to see how it all works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:cfe3b7ae-05e5-406a-9dcd-e3a646b9d16c</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/02/18/atom-like-rss-feeds-for-thisiskent-co-uk-news-stories</link>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sending trackbacks to the sites that you bookmark in del.icio.us</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I know they have their problems (I had 26 good and 38428 spam when they were enabled on my site) but I&amp;#8217;ve always liked the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trackback&quot;&gt;trackbacks&lt;/a&gt; (and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pingback&quot;&gt;pingback&lt;/a&gt; alternative).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;A few months back I started thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/ydn-delicious/message/1447&quot;&gt;sending trackbacks when bookmarking pages in del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt;.  Having been told that, although it was something that had been considered, it wasn&amp;#8217;t likely to be added anytime soon I decided to take a look at adding the functionality myself.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sixapart.com/pronet/docs/trackback_spec&quot;&gt;trackback specification&lt;/a&gt; states that I must send the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permalink&quot;&gt;permalink&lt;/a&gt; of my &amp;#8216;post&amp;#8217; to the resource that I&amp;#8217;m tracking back to.  By design, individual posts (or bookmarks) in &lt;a href=&quot;http://del.icio.us&quot;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; aren&amp;#8217;t addressable by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Identifier&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  So, the first step was to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2007/09/04/permalinks-for-del-icio-us-bookmarks-posts&quot;&gt;add permalinks to my del.icio.us bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;.  This was a kludgy, manual fix that added permalinks to all my old bookmarks: it didn&amp;#8217;t work for any new bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;From here, I spent some time &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2007/09/05/patching-the-del-icio-us-firefox-extension-to-add-permalinks&quot;&gt;hacking around with the del.icio.us firefox extension&lt;/a&gt; to get it to automatically generate these permalink tags.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The final stage was to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2007/12/18/extracting-my-del-icio-us-permalinks-functionality-into-its-own-firefox-extension&quot;&gt;extract the hacked-in functionality into its own extension&lt;/a&gt; (an extension of an extension &amp;#8211; cool huh).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Somehow, it took until about a month ago for me to realise that I now had everything in place to actually add trackback support to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/3615&quot;&gt;del.icio.us firefox extension&lt;/a&gt;.  I started looking at it last week and I&amp;#8217;ve just finish up the proof of concept this morning.  At present, it scans the page you&amp;#8217;re bookmarking looking for an anchor tag with rel=trackback (because this is easier than trying to parse the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/span&gt;).  If it finds one then it uses the url-tag from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/delicious-permalinks&quot;&gt;del.icio.us permalinks&lt;/a&gt; extension to construct the permalink for your (to-be-created) bookmark and promptly goes off to send a trackback.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The code is over in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisroos.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/delicious-trackbacks/&quot;&gt;google code repository&lt;/a&gt;.  It&amp;#8217;s very rough around the edges so I&amp;#8217;m holding off providing a compiled version just yet.  If you really want to play along then you can follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Install the del.icio.us firefox extension (to be fair, I&amp;#8217;m going to assume that you&amp;#8217;re probably at this stage already)&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Install the del.icio.us permalinks extension&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Checkout out the del.icio.us trackbacks source&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Find your Firefox extensions directory&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Create a textfile called delicious-trackbacks@googlegroups.com&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Add the path to the checked out project del.icio.us trackbacks project to this textfile&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Restart firefox&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Hope it all works and doesn&amp;#8217;t destroy your computer :-)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I&amp;#8217;ve created a real simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisroos.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/scratch/trackback-server/&quot;&gt;trackback server&lt;/a&gt; (well, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mongrel.rubyforge.org/&quot;&gt;mongrel&lt;/a&gt; handler) and a dummy page that includes a link to this server so that you can see the trackbacks being sent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 09:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:be4e61ba-08ff-4e98-b8f1-81a67147bc4a</guid>
        <author>Chris Roos</author>
        <link>http://blog.seagul.co.uk/articles/2008/02/04/sending-trackbacks-to-the-sites-that-you-bookmark-in-del-icio-us</link>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

